<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Security on Roderick Schaefer</title>
    <link>https://kciredor.com/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Security on Roderick Schaefer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kciredor.com/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Throwing 500 vm&#39;s at your fuzzing target being an individual security researcher</title>
      <link>https://kciredor.com/blog/throwing-500-vms-fuzzing-target-individual-security-researcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kciredor.com/blog/throwing-500-vms-fuzzing-target-individual-security-researcher/</guid>
      
        <description>Adobe Reader progress One year ago I blogged about my many attempts and failures at fuzzing Adobe Reader and finding exploitable security issues.
Meanwhile, I realized that writing your own fuzzers is the way to go as confirmed by my first CVE-2018-19713 for Adobe Reader. Found the bug using &amp;lsquo;What The Fuzz&amp;rsquo; targeting a custom plugin I coded which integrates with Adobe Reader.
So what&amp;rsquo;s the next step?
Fuzzing FoxitReader Excellent research has been shared on exploiting FoxitReader by @steventseeley, which inspired me to switch from Adobe to Foxit as a target.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuzzing Adobe Reader for exploitable vulns (fun != profit)</title>
      <link>https://kciredor.com/blog/fuzzing-adobe-reader-for-exploitable-vulns-fun-not-profit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kciredor.com/blog/fuzzing-adobe-reader-for-exploitable-vulns-fun-not-profit/</guid>
      
        <description>Binaries vs websites It has been half a year since my last blog post covering an IDOR in a website API. About time to write about something new and hopefully interesting! Having switched my focus from websites to binaries a new world opened up to me.
The reason I switched is my passion for low-level engineering. Reading through disassemblies, walking along with code being executed in a debugger, memory corruption, etc.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking over every Ad on OLX (automated), an IDOR story</title>
      <link>https://kciredor.com/blog/taking-over-every-ad-on-olx-automated-an-idor-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 15:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kciredor.com/blog/taking-over-every-ad-on-olx-automated-an-idor-story/</guid>
      
        <description>Public disclosure Hi again! Thank you for reading my third blog post. Happy to share all the details with you on the Insecure Direct Object Reference attack (IDOR) as mentioned in my first blog. It has been resolved by OLX and publicly disclosed on HackerOne, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s time for a write-up!
Some context OLX powers the LetGo website for a couple of countries including The Netherlands. LetGo is an eBay like website, allowing you to buy new stuff and let go of old stuff.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First bounty, time to step up my game</title>
      <link>https://kciredor.com/blog/first-bounty-time-to-step-up-my-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2017 15:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kciredor.com/blog/first-bounty-time-to-step-up-my-game/</guid>
      
        <description>What happened Hello again and thanks for reading my second blog post! After publishing my first blog I kept on trying to hack different companies and websites. Not as easy as I had hoped for! It took me quite some time to find another security issue after the IDOR in my first month. This SOME issue I found is not to be made public, so I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to mention company details and will have to mask url&amp;rsquo;s etc.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first month as a full-time bug bounty hunter</title>
      <link>https://kciredor.com/blog/my-first-month-as-a-full-time-bug-bounty-hunter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 15:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kciredor.com/blog/my-first-month-as-a-full-time-bug-bounty-hunter/</guid>
      
        <description>Introduction Thank you for taking the time to read my first blog post. My name is Roderick Schaefer, known as kciredor in the exciting world of security bug bounties. I&amp;rsquo;m new and working hard to get very much involved. By sharing my journey and considerations so far, I&amp;rsquo;m hoping for more interested people to give it a shot!
My background lies in software engineering with experience in development (go, python) and operations (linux, puppet/chef, docker/kubernetes).</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>